

# Tushal N Shah

CONTACT

#282, 2nd H Cross, 3rd Stage, 3rd Block Basaveshwaranagar Bangalore 560079 tushalshah@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/tushalshah tushalnshah.github.io/resume +91-9986878956

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Passionate Experienced and professional with over 7 years of valuable experience in monitoring project performance & QA to ensure company success. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate as part of a productive team. Accustomed to handling IT support, managing IT projects, and supporting various engineering departments with IT tools and applications. Experienced in working directly with clients to ensure all the goals of a project are achieved and met within scope and budget.

## STRENGTH

- Exhibits strong initiative to ensure efficient and effective completion of task.
- Team player with good organisational skills.
- Capacity and maturity to effectively interface with people at various levels
- Drive and desire to improve professionally.
- Strong Analytical abilities.
- Willingness to take an initiative

## TECHNICAL EXPOSURE

- Project Management: JIRA, Smart Sheet, Excel, Outlook, Teams, Zoom
- Tools: LAMP, Eclipse, Postman, HeidiSQL, VSCode, Docker, WinSCP, PUTTY
- Software Testing: Manual Testing, API Testing, Responsive Testing
- Data Base: MySQL, Postgres SQL
- Test Management Tool: JIRA, Bugzilla, Youtrack
- Cloud Platform: AWS, Digital Ocean
- CRM: LeadSquare
- Virtualization: Virtual Box, VMware Player
- Operating System: Windows, Ubuntu, Cent OS

## WORK EXPERIENCE

Unext | Jigsaw

Apr. 2022 — Present

Assistant Project Manager

- Worked in collaboration with the senior project manager to define project goals and establish a timeline and plan to achieve them.
- Worked to ensure successful project execution according to established objectives, timelines, and costs.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to achieve project goals in a timely and effective manner.
- Provided project updates to stakeholders and supervisors.
- Worked well independently and also with others.

Tushal N Shah

#### **IT Manager**

- Implementing new & better product design & functionality.
- Sign-off on Applications on every major or minor release.
- Create formal reports for various stakeholders in the company.
- Strategizing with Team members and assigning tasks based on priority & severity.
- Setting up Internal meetings, Demos & Discussions among the team & stakeholders.

## Jigsaw Academy

Aug, 2019 — Mar, 2021

**Quality Engineer** 

- Create Test Cases and refine the product developed based on Issues & Interactions faced earlier.
- Sign-off on Applications on every major or minor release.
- Identify bottlenecks & bugs in product developed proactively.
- Create formal reports for various stakeholders in the company.
- Testing of complete application from end to end and assisting in resolving bugs.

#### Codeveda Pvt Ltd

May, 2017 — Jul, 2019

Software Test Engineer

- Engaging with teams in discussions to provide constructive inputs, strategize and plan day to day activities of projects to deliver expected outputs within established time frame.
- Complete and deliver accurate work at accepted levels.
- Conducting Meetings with clients for understanding requirements, Training & providing Demo of Web Applications built.
- Testing of complete application from end to end and assisting in resolving bugs.
- Planning of Data Migration and Data Uploads for Projects.

#### VIA.com

Jan, 2015 — Apr, 2017

Software Test Engineer

- Defect reporting and Tracking using Bugzilla for managing testing activities.
- Experience in Software Testing, well versed in manual testing along with experience in conducting Black Box Testing Smoke, User Interface, Functional, System,
- Performance and Regression Testing.
- Resolving the Client logged issues on priority on the request.
- Performed Domain Validation, Uptime testing, Regression and Defect Testing in client domain.

# Flight Raja Travels Private Limited

Dec, 2009 — Nov, 2013

Associate Accounts Executive

- Daily International Flights, IRCTC, Bus, Mobile Top ups, DTH reconciliation
- Reporting on a daily basis average transactions, sales, commission earned and net retention

#### Standard Chartered Bank

Sep, 2007 — Jul, 2009

Customer Relationship Manager

- Handle customer inquiries, complaints, billing questions and payment extension/service requests.
- Interface daily with internal partners in accounting, operations and consumer affairs divisions.

Tuchal N Shah

2

## **EDUCATION**

BCA	2011 — 2014
SunRise University	
BCOM	2004 — 2007
Rajajinagar Pre-University College	
II PUC	2003 — 2004
Sheshadripuram Pre-University College	
STD X	2001 — 2002
Carmel High School	

## **ACHIEVEMENTS & REWARDS**

- Appreciation Award for handling projects at expected levels at Codeveda Pvt Ltd.
- Multiple Appreciation Awards as well as Employee of the Month at Ample Softwares.
- Earned praise from management for taking the initiative to streamline office operations at VIA.com.
- Commitment to quality. "Consistently achieved high quality assurance ratings from Standard Chartered Bank."

## **HOBBIES**

- 1. Reading Self Improvement/Productivity/Tech Related Articles
- 2. Trying out DIY Projects
- 3. Photography

# **LANGUAGES**

English, Hindi, Kannada, Gujarati

# **REFERENCES**

References available upon request.

Tushal N Shah 3